imrg.org 2017-03-10

# IMRG Privacy Policy

Home  ›  IMRG Privacy Policy 

## Introduction

We are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. This policy sets out our approach. “We” in this context are IMRG ltd. We are the trade association for online retail, a membership organisation, and we are the administrators of the policy. In the policy, we’re referred to as “The Administrator”.

We are committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to the web site in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”).

This policy contains the following pages:

  1. Information we may collect about you and reasons/purposes for processing information
  2. Type/classes of information processed
  3. Who the information is processed about
  4. Disclosure of your information.
  5. Undertaking research
  6. Consulting and advisory services
  7. Transfers
  8. Accessing and amending your personal information
  9. Disclosure to Third Parties
  10. Protection of personal information
  11. External Websites
  12. Opt-In
  13. Cookies

### How to contact us

If you have any questions, comments or requests regarding this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us in any of the following ways:

  * by email at [webmaster@imrg.org](mailto:webmaster@imrg.org)
  * by telephone on (0) 203 696 0980 between the hours of 09:00 and 17:00
  * by writing to us at: 2 Ching Court, 49 – 53 Monmouth Street, Covent Garden, London, WC2H 9EY

### Information we may collect about you and reasons/purposes for processing information

We process personal information to enable us to provide our services as a trade association which includes administering membership records, promoting our services, maintaining our accounts and records and supporting and managing our employees. We also process personal information in the course of selling, hiring or exchanging it. We do not collect any sensitive personal information such as information on your racial or ethnic origins, political opinions, religious beliefs, trade union affiliations, sexual life, health or criminal history.

Data is collected via;

  * information that you provide when becoming a registered user (including, for example, your name, address, telephone number and email address)
  * information provided when filling in forms or boxes on the site, for example at the time of requesting or subscribing to any service
  * information that you contribute to the site including, for example, information posted or submitted to the site as a registered user
  * information from surveys that we use for research purposes, if you choose to respond to them
  * communications you send to us, for example to report a problem with or submit a comment regarding the site
  * if you sign up to become a member or purchase a report through the IMRG website, in order to set up the payment we may do one of the following with our trusted secure payments partners: 
    1. Card Payment through WorldPay Portal
    2. Invoice
  * 3rd party events or partnerships

### Type/classes of information processed

We process information relevant to the above reasons/purposes. This information may include:

  * personal details
  * goods and services
  * membership details
  * details of complaints
  * financial details
  * education and employment details

### Who the information is processed about

We process personal information about:

  * members and supporters
  * employees
  * customers and clients
  * professional advisers and consultants
  * complainants and enquirers
  * suppliers
  * donors and lenders

### Disclosure of your information.

We sometimes need to share the personal information we process with the individual themselves and also with other organisations. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the Data Protection Act (DPA). What follows is a description of the types of organisations we may need to share some of the personal information we process with for one or more reasons.

Where necessary or required we share information with:

  * current, past and prospective employers
  * educators and examining bodies
  * suppliers and service providers
  * financial organisations
  * central government
  * sponsors

### Undertaking research

Personal information may also be processed to undertake research. For this reason, the information processed may include name, contact details, and business details. This information is about survey respondents. Where necessary or required this information may be shared with customers and clients, agents, service providers, survey and research organisations.

### Consulting and advisory services

Information is processed for consultancy and advisory services that are offered. For this reason, the information processed may include name and contact details. This information may be about customers and clients. Where necessary this information is shared with the data subject themselves, business associates and other professional advisers, current, past or prospective employers and service providers.

### Transfers

It may sometimes be necessary to transfer personal information overseas. When this is needed information is only shared within the European Economic Area (EEA). Any transfers made will be in full compliance with all aspects of the data protection act.

### Accessing and amending your personal information

We will process your personal data for the purposes set out in the clauses above. If however, you have any queries or requests in relation to Data Protection please notify our Head of Membership Services at: 2 Ching Court, 49 – 53 Monmouth Street, Covent Garden, London, WC2H 9EY.

### Disclosure to Third Parties

We may disclose your information too necessary third parties to enable us to provide you with membership value. Any events where data is to be disclosed to a 3rd party after the fact will have an opt in function. We also reserve the right to access and disclose to third parties your information to comply with applicable laws including but not limited to disclosure in accordance with the Act, the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 and lawful authority requests, to safeguard the proper operation of our systems and to protect ourselves and our clients.

### Protection of personal information

We use our reasonable endeavours, to ensure proper storage and careful disclosure of your personal information in order that nothing improper happens to your private information. These security measures mean that we may occasionally have to ask you for proof of identity before we are able to disclose personal information to you.

### External Websites

This privacy policy only applies to this website. The website may contain links to external websites. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We recommend that you check the privacy policy of any other websites you may visit through the website. The inclusion of links to such websites does not imply any endorsement of the material on such sites nor any association with their owners or operators. If you have any complaints relating to such sites, please contact them directly.

### Opt-In

If you tick the opt-in box the Administrators will provide your information to selected third party event sponsors. We or they may contact you by mail, telephone or e-mail to let you know about services and products which may be of interest to you. You have the right to ask for a copy of the information held by us about you in our records in return for the payment of a small admin fee. You also have the right to correct any inaccuracies in the information.

## Cookies

IMRG use cookies across our websites to improve their performance and enhance your user experience. IMRG have created this policy to explain how we do this.

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files which a website may put on your computer or mobile device when you first visit a site or page. The cookie will help the website to recognise your device the next time you visit.

Cookies serve many functions, for example, they can help us to remember your username and preferences, analyse how well our website is performing and allow us to send you content that we believe will be most relevant to you.

Cookies may contain personal information, such as logging your username when logging in to the IMRG site.

### What sort of cookies does IMRG use?

  1. **Essential cookies**  
Some cookies are essential for the operation of our website and allow us to identify IMRG members, so we can ensure they can access the member-only pages. If a member opts to disable these cookies, the member will not be able to access all of the content that a membership entitles them to. By accepting the use of login functionality, you must agree to the setting of specific cookies which allow these areas to function
  2. **Performance Cookies**  
We utilise other cookies to analyse how visitors use our websites and to monitor website performance. This allows us to provide a high quality experience by customising our offering and quickly identifying and fixing any issues that arise. From tracking the most popular pages to finding out why some pages are receiving error messages, we use these cookies to highlight articles or site services that we think will be of interest to you based on your usage of the website.
  3. **Functionality Cookies**  
Functionality cookies allow us to remember your preferences. Cookies save you the trouble of typing in your username every time you access the site, and recall your preferences, such as which sections of the website you want to see when you log in.

IMRG also use third party cookies such as Google Analytics to help us monitor our website traffic. These third party cookies may help us with market research, revenue tracking, improving site functionality and monitoring compliance with our terms and conditions and copyright policy. For example, surveys or comparisons may be added by third parties as added functionality. We will endeavour to ensure full disclosure of any cookies from third party websites.

### Can visitors block cookies?

When you accessed our site, you should have seen an overlay which explained that by continuing to access our site, you are consenting to our use of cookies. You can choose to disable cookies.

Please remember that if you do choose to disable cookies, you may find that certain sections of our website do not work properly.

Click here for more information on our [Cookie Policy](https://policy.cookiereports.com/4fc509ad-en-gb.html)
